《女子监狱》
第二季第八集
医生建议双侧输卵管至卵巢摘除术
The doctor recommends a bilateral salpingo-oophorectomy.
谁会不喜欢有"摘除"这个词的手术呢
Who doesn't love a surgery with "Ooph" in it?
惩教署对这个有些限制...
The, uh, DOC has set certain limits on invasive...
不能给你做
It's not gonna happen.
你并非没得选  我们可以继续化疗
You're not out of options. We'll stick with the chemo.
"我们"
"We"?
你卵巢里也有癌症吗
You got cancer in your ovaries, too?
我是你的辅导员  我是帮你渡过难关的
I'm your counselor. I'm here to help you through this.
没什么"渡过难关"
There is no "Through this."
我会死
I'm gonna die.
别这样  你能长命百岁呢
Hey. Come on, now. You could live for years.
-开他妈的什么玩笑  -注意语言
- That's a fucking lie. - Language!
我知道这很艰难
Look, I know this is difficult for you.
我堂兄得了肺癌  情况糟糕
My cousin had lung cancer. It didn't look good for him,
但他坚持化疗
but he stuck with the chemo
现在又在奥尼昂塔修屋顶了
and now he's back fixing roofs in Oneonta.
你堂兄真是走了好运
Lucky duck, your cousin.
而我  走的是霉运
Me? Dead duck.
你得尽量保持积极  没人知道未来如何
You have to try to remain positive. No one knows the future.
医生知道
Doctors know the future.
他们认为我需要做手术
They think I need the surgery.
但愿我可以帮你
I wish I could help you.
但你帮不了  永远都是如此
But it's out of your hands. It's always out of your hands.
你们都一样
You're all the same...
没用
useless.
罗莎  我牙里卡菜了吗
你怕他们觉得你不帅吗  老天啊  马尔科
是你把菠菜放在蛋里的
说起来  这样很好吃啊
谢谢  宝贝
等下  还真卡了菜  我帮你...
好了  完美
这个给你
天哪  马尔科
你会做得很好的
第一次谁都会紧张  但接着你会爱上这感觉的
-知道吗  -知道
- Okay? - Mmm-hmm. Okay.
别忘了你的墨镜
好看吗
Ahora si?
事前一吻  事后一吻
好了
Okay.
动手吧
-所有人都趴在地上  -好好
- Suits, on the floor! Down! - Okay!
钱放袋子里
趴着别动
Just stay down.
不要染了墨的  我可不想要蓝色的钱
No dye packs. Don't want no Smurf money.
快点
快
把袋子装满
Fill the bag.
我们走吧
走吧  宝贝
不要
Don't!
有警卫
你他妈给我的枪怎么没子弹
抢劫拿着空枪有什么好处
让你看起来很酷
你不信任我
枪支很危险
要的就是危险
宝贝  别生气嘛  看看这么多钱
你闻闻
-好棒的气味  -宝贝  棒极了
比黑色达卡还棒
天哪
你在流血
我们得送他去医院
他中枪了
He got hit?
有多糟  马尔科
我们可以带他去那个兽医那里
We can take him to that vet.
那个兽医在哪
为什么不去兽医那里  安迪
马尔科
Marco.
我们怎么办  马尔科  告诉我
先给我事后吻  事前一吻  事后一吻
你会没事的
你这么坚强
为我撑住  亲爱的
马尔科
Marco?
看起来不错嘛  红妈  发新芽了你看
Looking good, Red. You got a green thumb. Look at this.
这不是复杂的事
It's not rocket science.
那是什么
What's that?
我在想  我可以
I was thinking I could take a
占用一点地方自己种点东西
little area for my own guys to bust out a little.
种什么
What are you planting?
蔬菜
Vegetables.
别担心  我会亲自照顾的
Don't worry, I'll take care of 'em myself.
早上过来给它们唱首歌
Come in in the morning, I'll sing 'em a little song...
每天早上吗
Every morning?
等天暖和点儿  我就把它们移到室外
When it gets warmer, I'll move 'em outside.
你确定不会太早吗
Are you sure it's not too early?
因为如果他们在这里长得太大
Because if they grow too big in here,
移栽可就难办了
they might not transplant well.
不就是一点蔬菜嘛  比如西葫芦
It's just little bitch vegetables like squash.
花椰菜可不是好处理的
Broccoli is no pussy.
别担心  我知道自己在做什么
Don't worry, I know what I'm talking about.
这个盆对这株幼苗来说太大了
This pot is way too big for this seedling.
你得确保排水没问题...
You gotta make sure you're getting proper drainage here...
别动
Don't!
那是吉米的盆  是豆茎
That's Jimmy's pot. It's a bean stalk.
她觉得自己要从巨人那里偷琴呢
She thought she was going to steal a harp from a giant.
整个简直...
It was a whole... just...
好吧
Okay.
要是你担心排水系统
If you're worried about the drainage,
不如给我买些小点的花盆
maybe you could buy me some smaller pots.
这些花盆应该没什么问题
Yeah. They'll probably do just fine.
把你的种子给我吧  我会给你播种的
Leave your seeds. I'll get your plants going.
别了  我喜欢亲力亲为
Nah. Truth is, I like doing it myself.
有益身心
Therapeutic.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
干得不错
Good job.
我得说
I have to say,
这事还挺让人开心的
there is something gratifying about this, you know?
洗别人的衣服
Washing someone else's clothes,
为他人服务
being of service to another human being.
等你洗到
Well, just wait till you
全是大姨妈的裤子
come across some of them period-soaked panties
或者沾了屎的内裤再看你有多开心吧
or the shit stains on the undies and see how gratified you are.
我懂你的意思  苏苏
I get what you're saying, Soso.
拿来脏东西  再洗干净
Taking something dirty, making it not dirty no more.
说到洗
And speaking of washing.
看到小卖部里新进了除臭剂吗
You see they got a new kind of deodorant down at commissary?
爽身粉味儿的
Powder fresh scent.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Is that right? - Yeah.
我找时间去看看
Yeah, I may have to go check that out.
止汗剂对人体非常不好
Guys, antiperspirant is so bad for you.
超级有毒
You know, it's completely toxic.
我们的身体应该自由呼吸
Our bodies are meant to breathe free.
呼吸  是啊
Breathe, yeah.
这话让我希望
Yeah. You know, that makes me wish
我们这儿能有些窗
that we had some windows down
好通通风
here so we could air out the place, you know?
她们想说你很臭
Yeah, they're trying to say you stink.
真的吗
I do?
我们知道刚来这儿不容易
We know it's hard to get out of that depression funk thing
脱离那种绝望
when you first get here but...
你很臭
You reek.
去洗澡吧
Go take a shower.
好了  塔琪  别说了
All right, Tucky. Lay off.
你说什么  琳恩  你才闭嘴
Excuse me? Leanne, you lay off.
因为我认识的琳恩会告诉这个脏妞
'Cause the Leanne I knew would've told this dirty hippie
去洗洗她的下面
to go wash her hairy pits and her parts.
但你现在想交新朋友了是吗
But instead, you're off making new friends now, aren't ya?
怎么样
How's that going?
感觉就不太好
Can't imagine well,
因为真朋友不会兜圈子
because a real friend doesn't have to dance around the subject.
真朋友会说实话
And a real friend just tells it like it is.
学着点儿
Watch and learn.
你闻着跟乌龟缸似的  赶紧他妈去洗个澡吧
You smell like a fucking turtle tank. Go take a fucking shower.
一个80岁老太一个月忘洗澡了
You try washing an 80-year-old woman
你却想给她洗澡
when she's forgotten to shower for a month.
这儿出了些怪事
Strange things grow in the folds.
我们把吉米的事瞒了好多年了
We hid Jimmy's condition for years.
她到处晃的时候我们花半天去找她
Spent half our days tracking her down when she wandered,
想让她及时赶回来点名
trying to get her back in time for count,
看着她日况愈下
watching her get worse every day.
她要怎么吃饭  要怎么照顾自己
How is she gonna eat? How is she gonna take care of herself?
她会流落街头  然后
She'll end up on the street and then...
我猜撑不过一周
My guess, dead in a week.
别误会  他们干的事非常恶心
Don't get us wrong, it's disgusting what they done,
而她是  曾是一个很好的女人
and she is, was, a lovely woman.
所以提前释放只是踹了就跑
So compassionate release is really just a dump and run?
更像是踹开
More like dump and sidle
再偷偷溜走  他们就是这样的人
away like the sneaky, shitty spiders they are.
我认识一个记者  他也许能帮忙
I know this guy, a reporter. He might be able to help.
《疯老太获释》
"Demented Granny Set Free,"
可不是什么性感标题  连新闻都称不上
ain't a sexy headline and it ain't news.
没人关心老太太
No one gives a shit about old ladies.
我们让别人想到他们都难逃一死
We remind everyone that they're gonna die.
我不这么看
I don't feel that way.
我觉得在老人身边很舒服
I find it comforting to be around old people.
很高兴能帮上忙
Glad we could be of service.
我奶奶快死了
My grandmother is dying.
很遗憾
Sorry to hear that.
她教我织东西
She taught me how to knit.
我给我的毛绒猴子织了一条毯子
I made a blanket for my stuffed monkey.
花了我六个月
It took me six months.
然后我妈在庭院当旧货卖了两角五分
And then my mother sold it at a yard sale for a quarter.
你妈可真讨厌
Your mum sounds like a twat.
有时是的
She can be.
但我奶奶不是
But not my grandmother, no.
我爷爷死时
When Granddad died, she
她自学投资股票
taught herself how to invest in the stock market
变得非常在行
and got really, really good at it.
她在韦尔弗利特买了套房子
She bought herself a house in Wellfleet and...
还开始划皮划艇了
she started kayaking.
她以前总跟我说  "出去见见世面  帕波
She always used to say to me, "Go out and eat the world, Piper.
别为了男人在家做家庭主妇"
"Don't you get stuck at home with some man."
后面那句话我可能听得有些片面了
I may have taken that last part too literally.
查普曼
Chapman.
我猜猜
Let me guess,
亲爱的查普曼小姐  没人能休假
"Dear Miss Chapman, no one gets furlough.
你不行  别人不行  尤其是你不行
"Not you, not anyone, but especially not you.
敬上  惩教署  差不多吗
"Love, the DOC." Am I warm?
-你可以休假了  -真有趣
- Got your furlough. - Funny.
少讽刺了
Hey, watch the sarcasm.
我拨了几通电话  托了一点关系
I made a few phone calls, moved the process along.
你可以去跟奶奶告别了
You get to go and say goodbye to your nana.
天哪
Oh, my God!
我的天哪
你说  你说真的吗
Are you... Are you serious?
别提问  查普曼  道谢就好
Don't ask questions, Chapman. Just say, "Thank you."
谢谢
Thank you.
太谢谢了
非常感谢  海利先生  谢谢
Thank you, Mr. Healy. Thank you.
好了  不客气
Okay. You're welcome.
不客气  查普曼  不客气
You're welcome, Chapman. You're welcome.
他刚是说"休假"了吗
Did... Did he say furlough?
你也太聋了  亲爱的  谁能休假啊
You're deaf as a post, honey. No one gets a furlough.
早上好  早  你好啊
Good morning. Morning. How are you?
早上好啊美人
Good morning, sunshine.
这是什么
What's this?
是热可可
It's a hot chocolate.
有点甜  给我的...
A little sweet, for my...
-给你  -谢谢  乔尔
- You. - Thanks, Joel.
太烫了吗
Was it too hot?
这里面有烈酒吗
Is there Schnapps in this?
有
Yeah.
那这杯是我的
That one's mine.
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
宝贝  这是增添风味
Babe, it's for flavor.
别叫我宝贝
Don't call me babe.
你不能回我短信就不能叫我宝贝
You can't call me babe if you can't return my texts.
我要跟你说几次  我不发短信的
How many times do I have to tell you, I don't text.
好了  你要跟我聊天的话  就打电话吧
All right, if you wanna talk to me, call.
或者开车来我家
Or drive over to my house.
但是得半夜之后  等我室友睡着
You know, but after midnight, when my roommate's sleeping.
卡普托  你看看  看到没  你他妈看到没
Caputo! Look at this. Do you see this? Do you fucking see this?
你的鞋吗  我看到了  很漂亮
Your shoe? I see your shoe. It's a nice shoe.
-很漂亮  -高跟的
- Nice? - High.
这是一双鞋底粘了口香糖的鲁布托鞋
These are fucking Louboutins with gum on the sole.
我踩到了口香糖  双脚都没进门呢
I stepped in gum, not two feet into the building.
囚犯哪来的口香糖  口香糖是禁运品  卡普托
Where are the prisoners getting gum? Gum is contraband, Caputo.
这货是怎么进来
How the hell is it getting in,
被嚼  被吐在地上
chewed, dropped and stuck
然后粘在我昂贵的鞋上了
to the bottom of my very expensive shoe?
-我不知道  -所以我才担心
- I don't know. - And that's what concerns me.
我在执行记过配额指标呢
I'm enforcing your shot quota.
我已经尽我所能了
I'm doing everything I can.
那就再加把劲  掌握控制权
Well, do better. Take control.
你  你在这儿上班吗
You, do you work here?
-是的  女士  -别叫我"女士"
- Yes, ma'am. - Don't call me "Ma'am."
我不是来买你东西的大妈
I'm not an old lady you're bagging groceries for.
你是狱警  你的工作是执行规定
You are a correctional officer. Your job is to enforce the rules.
-你知道都有些什么规定吗  -知道
- Do you know what the rules are? - Yes.
因为现在随便看向哪儿
Because, right now, looking in an arbitrary direction,
都能看到大耳环和不允许化的妆
I see large earrings, I see unapproved makeup.
只有我看到了吗  是我有透视眼吗
Am I the only one who sees this? Do I have super vision?
我跟《第六感》里那男孩一样
Am I like the boy in The Sixth
能看到别人看不到的东西吗
Sense who sees infractions no one else sees?
是我走进了奈特・沙拉马拉马的电影
Am I in a fucking M. Night Shalamalama movie,
还是那个囚犯搽了绿色眼影
or is that inmate wearing green eye shadow?
应该是叫沙马兰吧
I think it's pronounced Shyamalan.
我还是先回去干活了
I, uh, better get back to work.
菲格罗亚小姐  大家都化妆
Miss Figueroa, everyone wears makeup.
很好  那我就没疯
Oh, good, I'm not crazy.
那你会做些什么
So are you gonna do something about it,
还是站在这里当摆设呢
or are you just here for decoration?
囚犯  等等
Inmate, hold up.
那完全没必要
That was totally unnecessary.
我把她可怜巴巴的眼神搞得更惨兮兮了吗
Oh, did I make her sad puppy dog eyes look even sadder?
我知道你对她有些
Look, I know you have some
爱情卡通片的感觉
kind of pathetic Love Is cartoon crush on her,
但现在不是高中了
but this isn't high school.
做好本分  不然我就另觅他人
Do your job, or I will find someone who will.
叫这人洗个澡去
And make this one take a shower.
一直累死了  我到哪睡哪
So fucking tired all the time, I fall asleep everywhere.
我跟恋尸癖似的
It's like I'm a necrophiliac.
你们想到计划什么的了吗
You guys come up with a plan yet, or what?
上一个想法是假装我很胖
Last idea was to pretend I'm fat,
在扫帚柜里生下来  然后从他的假腿里偷送出去
have it in the broom closet, and then sneak it out in his leg.
他一定是在开玩笑
But I'm pretty sure he was kidding.
但他可能说到点子上了
But he could be onto something though, you know?
这里的人好像
People around here seem
总有办法把东西弄进来
to have all sorts of ways of gettin' shit in,
也许你能想办法反过来
so maybe you could figure out the reverse.
上面是给厨房里的  下面是我姑娘们要的
Top's extra for my kitchen, bottom's some perks for my girls.
可别出岔子
Don't want any drama.
不会的  只是生意
No drama, just business.
护士  你在采血还是给她纹身呢
Hey, lady, are you taking her blood or giving her a tattoo?
我尽力呢
I'm doing my best.
你的"尽力"烂爆了
Yeah, well, your best sucks.
也许你一会儿会开始呕吐  就不会这么多话了
Maybe you'll start vomiting soon so you can't talk so much, yes?
赶紧把头埋进桶里
Go stick your head in a bucket.
谢谢你捍卫我的静脉  桶仔
Thank you for defending my veins, bucket boy.
她就是个没用的贱人
Yeah, well, she's a useless bitch.
她是个酒鬼
She's a drunk.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
看着  她会在窗口把血放下
Watch, she'll drop off the blood at the window,
绕到后面放钱包的柜子
circle back to the cabinet where they keep their purses
然后背对别人
and then she'll turn her
喝点东西
back and she'll take a slug of something.
然后关掉柜子  往嘴里扔块口香糖
Then close it up and pop a piece of gum into her mouth.
定时定点  每隔20分钟左右
She's like clockwork, every 20 minutes or so.
我操  你一直在踩点啊
Shit! You've been casing the joint.
我们有的是时间  你又没那么有趣
We got time here. You're not that interesting.
好吧  如果你要打劫
Okay, okay. So if you were gonna pull off a heist,
就此时此地  你会怎么做
like, in this room, right now, how would you do it?
我死前最后一次打劫吗  这又不是电影  孩子
One last heist before I go? This isn't the movies, kid.
别这样吧  迁就我下  我也得了癌症呢
No, come on, humor me. I have cancer.
目标是谁  聪明鬼
Who's the mark, smartass?
女酒鬼  偷她的钱包吧
Drunky bitch. Yeah, let's steal her wallet.
行  我奉陪
Okay, fine. I'll play.
我们今天走运  来的狱警是福特
We're lucky today. I got CO Ford.
他每小时会走开去看看司机怎么样
He actually gets off his ass to check the driver once an hour.
用时五分钟  然后会去上个厕所
Takes five minutes. Then he takes a bathroom break.
那就是两分钟
So two minutes.
不错啊
Good.
然后他会买杯咖啡  最多四分钟
Then he takes a coffee, that's another four, tops.
前台是个抽烟的
And the receptionist is a smoker.
她每三小时准点去摸鱼
She takes a break every three hours, on the dot.
那我怎么知道哪个钱包是女酒鬼的
So how do I know which purse is Drunky's?
跟酒瓶放一块儿的
Feel for the one with the flask.
抽烟的那个上一次摸鱼是1小时15分钟之前
Smokey's last break was one-hour-fifteen ago.
那怎么办  我们就等着吗
So what, do we just... We just wait?
我们等着
We wait.
你从斯坦韦路走会快一点
It'd be faster if you go down Steinway.
但那里有建筑
Except there's construction.
安迪  你得想办法绕过去  行吗
Andy, you gotta find a way around it, okay?
没问题
No problem.
你俩能消停点吗  这可是公事
Will you two stop? Hey, this is work.
那就做事啊  傻逼  我搞得定
Work now, ass-play later. I got it.
好了  听着
Okay, listen.
银行里有三个出纳  一个保安
We're looking at three tellers and one guard.
保安我来对付  唐  你去拿钱
I'll cover the guard. Don, you do the cash. Okay?
我们得在中午前搞定
And we gotta do this before noon,
因为今天是周五  中餐后他们会加派人手
because it's Friday and they add extra people in after lunch.
你能应付保安吗
Can you handle the guard?
这个傻逼
This fucking guy.
我能应付贝赛德银行的那个保安吗
Could I handle the guard in Bayside?
第一国家银行的那两个
The two in First National?
在康美银行吓尿的可不是我  对吧  唐
Wasn't me who freaked out at Commerce Bank, was it, Don?
好了
Okay.
准备好出发了吗
We ready to roll?
走了
I'm off.
等下  还有一件事
Hold up. One more thing.
事前一吻  事后一吻
你们每次都要这样吗
Oh, you gotta do this every time?
这是好运
It's good luck.
靠边停  在这里停  就是那辆车
Pull over. Pull over here. There's the car.
安迪  你干什么  我们得换车  快啊
Andy, what are you doing? We gotta do the switch! Let's go.
等一下
I need a minute.
没时间等了  快点  没时间休息
Papi, we don't got minutes. Come on, there's no time to rest.
罗莎
Rosa!
他好像心脏病发了
I think he's having a heart attack.
快走
Let's go.
心脏病发
求你  别这样  亲爱的
Please, don't do this, Papi. Please, okay?
我们还要去看尼亚加拉大瀑布呢
We gotta see Niagara Falls, okay?
我们还要看山猫队的比赛呢  求你了  亲爱的
We got tickets to Cats. Please, Papi. Please.
天哪  别再发生了  别又来一次
Oh, my God! This can't be happening again. Not again.
找钥匙  我来开车
我是卡萝尔・查普曼
Hello, you've reached Carol Chapman.
请留下姓名  电话号
Please leave your name, number,
以及简短的留言  我会...
and an ever so brief message and I'll...
天哪  人都上哪去了
Oh, my God, where are they?
一个囚犯只能打一通电话  有人排队的
One call per inmate. There's a line.
这都算不上是电话
That wasn't even a call.
挂上电话  重新排队
You hung up. Get back in line.
我得给休假做些安排
I need to make arrangements for my furlough.
行吧
Fine.
维特利纳太干了  绿维特利纳是甜葡萄酒
Sure, it's dry for a Veltliner. Grüne Veltliner is a sweet wine.
我说了他不喜欢甜白酒
I told you he doesn't like sweet whites.
所以你才没拿到合同
That's why you didn't get the contract.
而她简直是在讲小说
Meanwhile, she's dictating a novel.
你  查普曼
You, Chapman...
那是口红吗
that lip gloss?
不不  我天生的唇色
No, no, no, no. These are just my lips.
那睫毛呢
What about the eyelashes?
-也是天生的  -好吧
- I was born with them. - Fine.
他不会让我失望的
He wouldn't have let me down.
我操  这应该能点火啊
Shit. It's supposed to light on fire.
简直是我见过的最蠢的事
It's the dumbest fucking thing I've ever seen.
你和费歇尔
Hey, am I wrong to assume
是不是凑成一对儿了
that you and Fischer have been riding the hobby horse?
我可不是八卦王  不过
I don't kiss and tell, but, uh...
我上了她
I fucked her.
才没呢
No, you didn't.
-我抓了她的奶  -才没呢
- I grabbed her boobs. - No, you didn't.
-真的  -真的
- No, I did! - Really?
比我厉害
It's farther than I got.
-吃醋了  -完全没有
- Jealous? - Nah. Not at all.
现在我知道她品位很烂了
Now I know she has horrible taste.
看到没
See?
我就说吧
Told you.
这是什么原理
How does that even work?
拜托  你才是电工的头儿
Come on, you're head of electrical.
我知道  不过原理到底是什么
Yeah, I know, but how's that work?
卢斯奇
Luschek!
囚犯
Inmate!
这里最好有12节电池  再数一遍
There better be a dozen batteries there. Count 'em again.
一  二  三...
One, two, three...
我操  三后面是几来着  我忘了
Fuck, man, what comes after three? I forgot.
你没在这里抽烟吧
You haven't been smoking out here, have you?
为什么说我抽烟
Why do you assume I'm a smoker?
因为你在奥斯维戈长大
'Cause you grew up in Oswego.
我戒了  把钱都花在威士忌上了
Well, I quit. More money for whiskey.
我闻到了烟味
I smell smoke.
那是睫毛膏吗  你怎么会有
Is that mascara? Why do you have mascara?
因为小卖部有卖
'Cause they sell it at commissary.
-好好管管你的人  -是
- Keep your people in line. - All right.
她的奶子怎么样
Now, what are those tits like?
狱警  他们也是人  这是苏珊・费歇尔
这些文章总是把的漫画腰斩
That article keeps on cutting off my comic.
他们都没脚了
Now they got no feet!
她穿了高跟鞋呢  现在我知道猪是指谁了
Oh, she's wearing heels! Now I get who the pig is.
你应该再让她背个钱袋
You should have her holding money bags, too.
亲爱的弗娜卡
"Dear Flaca,
我的室友一直在偷我货  我该怎么处理
"My bunkie's lifting my shit. How should I handle the situation?"
不能说"货"
You can't say, "Shit."
不然怎么说  "贱人"吗  因为弗娜卡说
Well, can I say, "Bitch"? 'Cause here's what Flaca say,
尽量说服贱人别再偷东西
"Try to reason with the bitch to lay off the sticky fingers,
但如果她不听
"But if she doesn't listen,
就拖她去个没人的地方
"You know, drag her to a place where no one can see,
给她一顿胖揍
"And bash her head real good."
耶稣看到了
Jesus saw that.
这些都不能写
You can't write any of that.
你知道管理员需要审核简报
You know the administration needs to approve all of this.
你让她去小卖部买把牢固的锁吧
Why don't you tell her to go buy a sturdy lock at the commissary?
我就这意思
That's what I'm saying.
买把锁  藏在袜子里  然后放倒那贱人
Buy a lock, stick it in a sock and slock the bitch down.
不  我们得完成这个  最晚明天必须完成
No. We have to finish this up. This has to be done by tomorrow.
不是周二才截止吗
I thought we had till Tuesday?
我周二不在
I won't be here Tuesday.
怎么  你要请事假
Oh, what, you takin' a personal day?
不  我拿到休假了
No, I got furlough.
-真的吗  -不
- For real? - No...
慢着  绝对不可能
Wait, no fucking way.
真的  我奶奶病了  我申请然后通过了
Yeah. My grandmother's sick. I applied and it went through.
我也申请了
I applied, too!
我还让人给典狱长打了电话  根本屁都没用
I even had people call the warden. That shit never works!
是啊  我几乎都放弃了
I know. I had almost completely given up.
现在  我可以去跟她道别
Now... Now I get to go, say goodbye.
告诉她我有多爱她
Tell her how much I love her.
五分钟内就道完别
Yo, get that shit out of the way in, like, in five minutes.
超快说完你要说的话
You know, say what you gotta say, like, super quick.
就说  "安息吧  奶奶
Then be like, "Peace, abuelita!
我会在夜店
"I'll be in the club with
点杯长岛冰茶  使劲扭屁股"
my Long Island and my fatty, making it clap!"
她的白屁股可扭不起来
No way that white ass is gonna clap.
姑娘们会嫉妒你的
Girls are gonna be pissed at you.
-我现在就有点想揍你  -我也是
- I kinda wanna punch you right now. - Me, too.
你最好小心点
You better watch your back.
-你拿到休假了  查普曼  -是的
- You got furlough, Chapman? - I did.
我在天主教堂待了好多年
I've been in the Catholic Church a lot of years
老实说这是我第一次见到上帝的奇迹
and this is my first honest-to-goodness miracle.
好好利用这一次
Use it well.
我会的
I will.
我会去找我奶奶
I'm gonna go and be with my grandmother
问她所有我没来得及问的问题
and ask her all the questions I never got to ask.
这是什么
What is that?
冰沙  甘蓝菜  枣子和杏仁乳
Smoothie. Kale and dates and, uh, almond milk.
-你抽烟吗  -不抽  但我有时会嚼烟草
- You smoke? - No, but I chew tobacco sometimes.
嚼烟草就白喝甘蓝菜了  不是吗
Chewing tobacco defeats the purpose of drinking kale, doesn't it?
我会想也许它们互相抵消
Well, I like to think that they cancel each other out, maybe.
你有什么事吗  还是...
Um, can I help you with something? Or...
禁运品
Contraband.
我觉得自己简直在玩"打鼹鼠"的游戏
I feel like I'm playing whack-a-mole here.
我在一处砸中了它  它又在另一处跑出来了
I beat it down in one place and it pops up in another.
你看到什么的话记得告诉我
You need to tell me if you see anything.
好的
Yeah, of course. Yeah.
想都别想保护谁
Don't you dare try to protect anyone.
我知道这很难  你在这里交到了朋友
I know it's hard. I know you make friends in this place.
-不  我没有...  -你有  时有发生
- No, I, I don't... I don't... - You do. It happens.
有时你都没意识到
Sometimes you don't even realize it's happening, and,
突然之间  就发现自己相信别人了
all of a sudden, you find yourself trusting somebody.
你问别人意见
You're asking somebody advice...
那个人可不是你的朋友  那个人...
That person is not your friend. That person...
怎么了
What?
我操
Fuck.
我了个大草
The fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
看看我  我还在这儿呢
Oh, hey, look at me, I'm still here.
我只是尽本分  莫里洛
I'm just doing my job, Morello.
费歇尔带罗莎来时从来不来查岗
Fischer never came to visit when she had Rosa.
你知道她会做什么吗
You know what she'd do?
一天结束  她会给我带希斯酒吧
She'd bring me a Heath bar and a cold Dr.
和冷的胡椒博士
Pepper at the end of the day.
是不是超体贴
Isn't that thoughtful?
也许你来查岗时也可以这么做
Maybe you could do that when you come to check on me.
-下一小时再见  莫里洛  -好吧
- I'll see you in an hour, Morello. - Okay, fine, fine.
也许你可以就给我
Maybe you could just bring
带个空瓶子来好让我撒尿
me an empty bottle that I could pee into.
我不能离开这车  对吧
I can't leave the van, right?
你可以下车到后面蹲坑
Oh, you can get out and take a squat in the back
然后再上车
and then get back in.
太好了  谢谢  太感谢你了
Okay, great. Thank you. Thank you so much.
我要去厕所了
Uh, well, I'm going off to the bathroom.
真是个蠢货
护士小姐  能来一下吗
Nurse? Nurse? Can you come over here, please?
没什么事吧
Is everything okay?
我的阀门好像漏了
I think my port is leaking.
没有啊  没什么问题
No, looks fine to me.
这戒指真漂亮
Oh, what a beautiful ring!
有多大  两克拉吗
What is that? Two carats?
是的
It is.
怎么  你还是珠宝贼
What, were you a jewel thief?
不  我对珠宝没什么兴趣  不过我喜欢闪闪的
Nah, that was never my main gig, but I like the bling.
-六千块  -少了
- Six grand? - Warm.
-七千  八千  -八千五
- Seven? Eight? - Eight and a half.
我未婚夫是大型连锁超市的地区经理
My fiance is a regional manager for Foodtown.
-他省了...  -他真厉害
- He had to save up for... - Good for him.
我有点渴了  能给我倒杯水吗
I'm a little thirsty. Can I have some water, please?
行
Yeah, sure.
假警报
It was a false alarm.
我操啊  小屁孩
The fuck, kid?
没想到我会为63块钱这么激动
I never thought I'd get so excited over $63.
-才20块  -这是你的分成
- $20? - That's your cut.
-所有事都是我干的  -整个行动是我策划的
- I did all the work! - I was the brains of the operation.
尤瑟夫・米瑞马迪
Yusef Miremadi.
都是她策划的
She was the brains.
你妈妈来了
Your mom is here.
医生要跟你们谈谈
The doctor needs to speak with you.
妈妈的乖宝宝
Mama's boy.
我会回来的  这可没完
I will be back. Okay, but this is not enough.
永远没完
It's never enough.
五万块
Fifty grand!
还没到家呢  先别激动
We're not home yet. Cool it.
这么认真
Oh, so serious.
来吧  事前一吻  现在该事后吻了
Come on, we kissed before. It's time for the after kiss.
你知道我不会这么做的
You know I won't do that.
别  这会带来霉运
No. It's bad luck.
别闹了  我们还要再开一段路
Cut it out. We gotta drive more!
就在这里停车
Pull over right here.
你因为抢劫而性致高昂  行
You're all hot from the job? Fine.
你干什么
What are you doing?
我不想操  我想抢银行
I don't wanna fuck now. I wanna rob that bank.
-我们才刚抢过  -再抢一家
- We just did one. - Let's do one more!
我们对这家银行一无所知  好吗
We don't know nothing about that bank. Okay?
我们不知道谁在工作  警报器在哪
We don't know who's working, where the alarms are. All right?
简直疯了  我不干
This is crazy. I'm not doing it.
我不需要你
Well, I don't need you.
你需要我的  罗莎
Yes, you do need me, Rosa.
你干什么
What are you doing?
看看你  因为拿到休假觉得自己碉堡了
Look at you thinking you're all hot shit 'cause you got furlough.
我真该给你剃个短短头
I ought to give you a skullet.
什么是短短头
What's a skullet?
就是光头只留小辫儿
A mullet with the top shaved.
就这样吧  我家人以为我出去会是彪悍的重罪犯
Well, you might as well. My family is expecting a hardened felon.
让他们满意一次也好
It would be nice to meet their expectations for once.
你在自由世界有48小时  有宏伟计划了吗
You got 48 hours in the free world, kid. You got big plans?
跟我的家人在一起
Be with my family...
看着我奶奶过世
watch my grandmother fade away.
别这样  太浪费了
Oh, come on. That can't be it.
你会跟你丈夫一起吗
You gonna stay with your husband?
不  他不是我丈夫
No... Well, he's not my husband.
我都不知道我们还是不是朋友
And I don't even know if we're friends anymore.
我想到我的家
I mean, when I think of my home,
我想到我们一起住的地方
I think of where we lived together,
但我不住在那里了
but I don't live there anymore.
我都不知道我的东西还在不在那里
I don't even know if my stuff is still there.
我的乳液还在不在洗手台上
I don't even know if my lotions are on the sink,
还是他全把我的东西收进袋子里
or if he took them all and he put them in a bag
漏得整个都是了
and they're all just leaking all over each other.
还是就把我的东西留在原处
Or if he just left them there.
他可千万别改变  或者做出  或者注意任何事
God forbid he should change, or do, or notice anything.
我俩现在的关系有点棘手
Things are a little complicated between us right now.
你怎么做到的  查普曼
So, how'd you do it, Chapman?
你给海利什么"好处"了吗
Did you give Healy a little reach-around?
天哪  才没有
God, no, no. No!
没有  他们可能真是终于同情我了
No, I think that they might've finally taken pity on me.
我将要失去我爱的人
I mean, I'm about to lose somebody that I love.
也许  这所监狱还是有点良心的
Maybe, maybe, this prison has a heart after all.
放屁吧
Bullshit!
我申请了两次
I applied twice.
我丈夫进行开胸手术
When my husband had open heart
以及我第一个孙子出生时
surgery and for the birth of my first grandchild.
他们让我滚蛋
They told me to go fuck myself.
从没抱过那孩子  但我真的很想抱
Never held the baby. And I love me some baby holding.
我也申请过
I applied, too.
没同意
Nothing.
申请干什么
What for?
我父亲进行了移植肺脏  但排斥了
My father had a lung transplant that didn't take.
我变性后咱俩就没说过话  他真的很拗
We hadn't spoken since I transitioned. He was a real hard-ass.
但最后  他开始找我
But in the end, he started asking for me.
他甚至叫我的新名字  索菲娅
He even used my new name, Sophia.
人之将死其言也善
People get soft, you know, when they dying.
如果我当时见到他了  或许...
If I could've seen him, I don't know...
会有种了却心结的感觉
may have felt like closure.
但我们这辈子是没多少机会了  不是吗
But we don't get a lot of that in this life now, do we?
这是我后悔清单里的一项
Add it to my list of regrets.
但是奶奶  也很重要
But grandmothers, they important, too.
你干什么
What are you doing?
找什么呢
What are you looking for?
说话啊
Use your words.
在哪
Where is it?
什么  香菜  西葫芦吗
What? The cilantro, the squash?
你是要砸碎每个花盆吗
Are you gonna smash every pot?
必须的
You bet your ass.
这次你最后一次骗我了  红妈
This is the last time, Red, you pull one over on me.
行吧  让我帮你
All right. Let me help you.
怎么  咱们现在干的不就是这个吗
What? Isn't this what we're doing now?
不是吗
Isn't this what we're doing?
这儿  最后一盆  你要亲手砸碎吗
Here, this is the last one. You wanna do the honors?
不要
No?
行了  就这样
Okay, then. That's that.
但愿你觉得有益身心
I hope it was therapeutic for you.
我不介意被批评  不是这回事
I don't mind being criticized, it's not that,
我只是觉得她要是这么坚持执行规定
I just think that if she's so set on enforcing the rules,
也许就不该在囚犯面前
then maybe she shouldn't undermine my authority
让我难堪
in front of the inmates.
有些人用暴力管制  有些人则用魅力
Some of us control with muscle, some of us control with charm.
咱俩就是靠魅力的
You know, you and me, we're charm.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
记过配额指标烂透了
This whole shot quota's a bad idea.
对大家都不好受
It's making things harder for everyone.
还有一大堆文书工作
And all the friggin' paperwork.
我倒是不介意  给了我坐下来的时间
I don't mind the paperwork. Gives me a chance to get off my feet.
如果你忙着做文书工作  牢里打起架
But what if you're tied up doing paperwork and a fight breaks out
发生暴乱了怎么办
and it turns into a prison riot?
你本可以阻止的  却没阻止成
And you could've stopped it, but you didn't,
因为你在办公室做文书工作
because you were in your office doing paperwork?
你有没有做过拯救全人类的英雄梦
You ever have those dreams where you save everybody?
有时吧
Sometimes.
有一次  我荣获了国会荣誉勋章
One time, I received the Congressional Medal of Honor.
真厉害
Nice.
干什么
What?
有话快说  有屁快放
You got something to say, out with it.
我们认为记过配额指标不合理
We don't think the shot quota's reasonable.
对情况没什么益处
It doesn't improve conditions.
会让囚犯和狱警之间产生怀疑
It creates mistrust between the inmates and the staff.
你想让她们相信你
You'd like them to trust you more?
我想让她们认为
Well, I'd like them to think
她们受管束是公正的
that when they're disciplined, it's justified.
不然的话  谁还会照章办事
I mean, otherwise, why follow the rules at all?
对我们也是如此
And the same goes for us.
我认为我被人吼是不公平的
I don't think it's fair that I was yelled at.
我要管理这座监狱
In order for me to run this facility,
你们所有人就得听我指示行事
I need all of you to comply with my directives
不管你们认为合不合理
whether you find them "Reasonable" or not.
规矩是上面定下来的
The rules come from the top down.
但这些规矩
Yeah, but there are rules
我们根本就不严格执行
that we don't even enforce consistently.
却被责怪...
And then we get blamed...
费歇尔  现在不是
Fischer! This is not the
适当的时机或地点来向我抱怨
appropriate time or place to air your complaint.
卡普托先生  抱歉  我是有话直说
Well, Mr. Caputo, I'm sorry, but I have to speak my mind.
你不能专横地惩罚别人
You can't just punish someone
就为了杀鸡儆猴...
arbitrarily to make an example of them...
你被解雇了
You're fired.
什么
What?
我警告过你了
I tried to warn you.
这个月的薪水会发给你
You'll be paid through the end of the month.
还有人强烈渴望直抒胸臆吗
Does anyone else have the burning desire to speak their mind?
很好
Good.
白人妞  给我吧  我来就行
Oh, Blanca, Blanca, I got that. I got that. Dámelo.
去洗搅拌器
Go clean the mixer.
那不是玛丽萨干的吗
拜托  那姑娘被关禁闭回来以后
Please. That girl's as useless as balls on a dildo
整个人跟假鸡巴一样废
since she came back from seg.
她才待了多久  三分钟
And she was there, what? Three minutes?
有事吗
Can I help you?
给你带了礼物
Brought you a gift.
我不需要陈年旧烟
I don't need no more stale-ass tobacco.
这算是补偿  新货  我保证
This is to make up for that. This is fresh, I promise.
在里面加了点薄荷  变成薄荷醇了
Put some peppermint in it, turned it into a menthol.
被狱警抓到了  你就要被记过了
CO catches you back here, you gonna get a shot.
你跟红妈现在关系不错啊
So, uh, you and, uh... you and Red on friendly terms now?
跟你无关
Doesn't concern you.
那女人还真知道怎么俘获人心
Damn, that woman knows how to run a game on people.
我可以给你讲几个故事
I could tell you some stories.
你听过
Hey, have you ever heard
蝎子和青蛙的寓言吗
of the fable of the scorpion and the frog?
怎么  我他妈是青蛙吗
What, I'm the fucking frog?
你俩狼狈为奸  我知道她在做些勾当
You two in cahoots. I know she's doing business.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你有卖家关系  她帮你散货
You've got a vendor connection and she's handling your sales.
我只是来做饭的
I'm just here to cook.
红妈干的事跟我毫无关系
Whatever Red's got going, got nothing to do with me.
要合伙人吗
You want a partner?
我保证我比她更好
I promise I'm a much better bet,
因为红妈只想要回她的厨房
because all Red wants is to get her kitchen back.
你给我好好听着
You listen to me.
你自以为知道些什么  其实并没有
Whatever you think you know, you don't.
我手不脏  没破事
I'm keeping my hands clean, my shit polished.
我跟供应商或者非法赃物流入都没关系
I got no connections with vendors or illegal swag coming through.
你们这些疯婆娘我一个都不信
And I don't trust any of you crazy bitches.
你俩都他妈是蝎子
You're both fucking scorpions.
操  我操我操  妈逼
Shit. Shit, shit, shit. Fuck.
整体来看
Hey, listen, in the grand scheme of things,
香烟是什么
I mean, what's a cigarette, really?
就是卷在纸里的植物
You know, it's a plant and some paper.
你想想我可能会干的各种恐怖事件
When you think about all the horrible things I could be doing.
随你抽吧  我无所谓了
Smoke all you want. I don't care anymore.
我被炒了
I got fired.
真好
Hey, good for you.
你不明白
You don't get it.
我现在该怎么办  我没有一技之长
What am I gonna do now? I'm not good at stuff.
你肯定不擅长这行
Well, for sure, you weren't great at this.
这可是褒奖你  相信我
But that reflects highly on you, trust me.
我有医保和牙保  还在还我的起亚车贷
I had medical and dental. I was paying off my Kia.
你是个好人
You're a decent human being, you know.
脱离这个吸食灵魂的破地方
Getting canned from this soul-sucking pit
是你身上发生的最好的事
is the best thing that ever happened to you.
回家去  洗个热水澡
Go home, take a hot bath,
开始找找专科学校
and start looking into technical colleges.
或者美容  学习腋窝和敏感区脱毛
Or cosmetology. Learn to wax armpits and vag lips.
外面大千世界等着你呢
There's a million things out there for you.
-我能问你一个问题吗  -问吧
- Can I ask you a question? - Yeah, shoot.
前不久  你是在跟我调情吗
Like, a while back, were you hitting on me?
不做梦就要死  对吧
We don't dream, we die, right?
我做得怎么样
So, how'd I do?
我想了一下
I thought about it.
真的假的
Seriously?
骗你的
Not in a thousand years.
不过谢了
But thank you.
苏珊  收拾东西离开这里
Susan, pack your shit and get the fuck out of here.
你会没事吗
Are you gonna be okay?
就这样了
It is what it is.
宝贝  你被炒了
Babe, you got fired?
真糟
Lame.
让我去看看他
Let me go see him.
我们得回去
We need to get back.
这是我越狱计划的一部分
It's all part of my escape plan.
他会用眼泪转移你的注意
He's going to distract you with his tears.
等我一下
Just give me a second.
简直是诅咒
It's the fucking curse.
我拉你入伙  我没吻你  但咱俩还是干了一票
I pull you in. I don't kiss you, but still, we did a job.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我说过  我生命中的男人全死了
I told you, all the men in my life die.
我不是你生命中的男人  好吗
I'm not a man in your life. Okay?
你自己说的  我就是个小屁孩
You said so yourself, I'm a little shitpot.
你这么年轻怎么能死
You're too fucking young to die.
所以我不会死的
So I'm not gonna die.
我不用做化疗了  我进入缓解期了
I'm done with chemo. I'm in remission.
罗莎  跟你一起很有意思
Listen, Rosa, it's been a lot of fun hanging out.
我受益良多
It's been a trip.
恭喜
Congratulations.
享受监狱
Enjoy prison.
享受生活  小屁孩
Enjoy your life, shitpot.
我该说什么
So, what should I say?
你说对了  我错了
You was right, I was wrong?
应该跟你合伙的  我显然没法一个人干
Should've stuck with the band. I'm clearly not a solo artist.
但至少你还活着  诅咒没克死你
But at least you're still alive. The curse never got you.
我从没跟你事后吻过  也许就是这样救了我
Well, I never did the after kiss. Maybe that's what saved me.
我为什么要那么做
Why did I do that?
你不想上我
You didn't wanna fuck me.
我想啊
Oh, but I did.
只是想在更大的钱床上
Just on a bigger bed of money.
我真贪婪
Greedy me.
我好想那气味  唐尼
I miss the smell, Donny.
我爱现金的气味
I love the smell of cash, man.
那种激情  表演  刺激
The excitement, the performance, the rush.
我在这里怎么找刺激啊
What am I gonna do in here for kicks?
查普曼一来就受到了
You know, Chapman been getting special treatment
特殊照顾
since the minute she got here.
她好像是第一个拿到休假的人
Figures she'd be the first to get furlough.
我真他妈浪费了
Man, I fucking blew it.
我离开了这破地方两周
I had a solid two weeks out of this joint,
但一半时间都在找你这个逼
and I wasted half that time looking for your sorry ass.
去死  是你自己破坏了假释条例
Fuck that. You done found time to violate your probation,
又滚回了这里
land your wide butt back up in here.
贱人  至少你还见过这围栏之外的日光
Bitch, at least you seen daylight outside this fence.
我申请休假整整六个月
Man, I tried for six months to get furlough.
显然一个死去的黑人老妈
Clearly a dead black mom
比不上一个病了的白人老太
ain't no competition for a sick, old white granny.
你和你家男人都不在一起了
You and your man aren't even together no more.
太浪费
What a waste.
要是我出去了  肯定和凯撒操一整天
If I got out, me and Cesar would be fucking all damn day.
我和迪艾保会没日没夜地操
Diablo and I would go all day and all night.
生病的奶奶
Sick abuela.
你他妈是怎么想到这个桥段的
The fuck you came up with that one?
天哪  查普曼  大家都恨透你了
Christ, Chapman, everybody hates your fucking guts.
是吗  还有什么新消息
Yeah, what else is new?
嫉妒与死亡一样强烈  所罗门之歌
"Jealousy is as fierce as the grave," Song of Solomon.
托妮・莫里森的吗
Toni Morrison?
是《圣经》  亲爱的
The Bible, sweetie.
这里人的爸妈过世了
Man, people's parents fucking go.
这里的病人得不到应有的照料
Got sick people in here who can't get proper treatment.
查普曼一生顺风顺水
Chapman ain't got no strife in her life,
但那贱人就是有一条康庄大道
but bitch gets the red carpet laid out for her.
歧视黑人啊
The new Jim Crow.
那贱人可能跪下了
Bitch probably got down on her knees.
含好了海利那粉粉的鸡巴
Took a mouthful of that pink Healy dick.
是啊  我是白人
Yes, I am white!
大家都知道
We have established that.
我也拿到了休假
And I got furlough, too.
看来白人特权又赢了
I guess white privilege wins again.
作为整个白种人的发言人
And as a speaker for the entire white race,
我想说很遗憾你们受到了不公平待遇
I would like to say I am sorry that you guys got the raw deal,
但我他妈爱我奶奶
but I love my fucking grandmother.
是啊  她也有些白
And, yeah... yeah, she may be a whitey, too...
但她是个人
but she's a fucking person...
她病了
and she's sick...
她需要我
and she needs me!
都他妈给老娘闭上嘴
So shut the fuck up!
跟我没关系
It's not my problem.
你和小维有矛盾  别扯上我
You and Vee got beef, don't drag me into your shit.
我以为波多黎各人讨厌黑人呢
I thought Puerto Ricans hated black people.
我们也不喜欢俄罗斯人
We don't like Russians neither.
-她是个恶霸  -你俩都是
- She's a bully. - You're both fucking bullies
而我不信你们任何人
and I don't trust neither one of you.
我说了会帮你  我也帮了
Now I said that I will help you and I did.
但我不会卷入什么
But I am not gonna get caught up
黑白种人大混战之中的
in the middle of some whitey versus blackie war.
你们都有黑历史  我可不想跟你们有关系
Y'all got history, I want nothing to do with that.
我会尽快弄出去的
I'll get it out as soon as I can.
给你三天
You've got tres días.
英文说就是"三天"
That's "Three days" In English.
是  夫人
Se, senora.
不过你就只能做到这份上吗
In the meantime, is that really the best that you can do?
什么
What?
我救了你一命  贱人
I saved your ass, bitch.
你的东西  安全得很
Here's your shit, all safe and sound.
你想让卡普托去你的温室大闹一场吗
You want Caputo playing hot and cold in your greenhouse?
咱们现在就能去
'Cause we can go right
你那小小的种植系统
back to your little planter system right now.
行吧  算我谢你了
Okay, okay. I appreciate the gesture.
给我点时间等风头过去
Give me a little time for things to cool down.
你要的东西来了
I've got your order coming.
交易还继续
Deal's still on.
咱俩没事吧  没事
We're good, you and me, huh? We're good.
海利先生  我不能休假  我想退掉
Mr. Healy, I can't take my furlough. I wanna give it back.
这儿有人比我更需要
There are people here who are way more needy.
这儿有人的父母生病了
There are people here whose parents are sick.
-孩子们...  -天哪  你什么毛病
- Children... - For Christ's sake, what is with you?
我都不明白你这次为什么要帮我
Look, I don't even understand why you did this for me.
你讨厌我  大家都不明白
You hate me! Nobody gets this!
查普曼  我早上
Chapman, I spent my morning
跟一位老太说她有末期癌症
telling an old lady that she has terminal cancer
还有惩教署不会报销她手术费用的
and that the DOC won't cover her surgery.
她说我没用
And she said I was useless.
你知道吗  她说得对
And you know what? She was right.
我开始这份工作时  充满了理想
When I started this job, I was very idealistic.
我想做出些改变
I was gonna make a difference.
但我就是个弄文书的  我填表
But I'm a paper pusher. I fill out forms.
我做的大部分事就是保持你们安全整洁
Most of what I do is, I keep you safe and clean.
偶尔  就那么偶尔一次
And occasionally, once in a blue moon,
我会有个机会把表格申请上去
I get an opportunity to give one of those forms an extra nudge.
-多数人会感激  -我很感激
- Most people would be grateful. - I was.
真的
I am!
但现在我变成了众矢之的
Until it turned me into a target!
不能退回休假
There's no taking back furlough.
你的车准备好以后
When your ride is ready,
你就能上车去看你生病的奶奶了
you be in that car on your way to see your sick grandmother.
姑娘们会窃窃私语  羡慕嫉妒
And girls will talk and they'll get jealous,
是的  她们甚至
and, yes, it's possible
可能会在你睡着时弄死你
they may even try to slock you in your sleep,
不过别理她们
but ignore them.
查普曼  人都有一死  错过了就来不及了
Chapman, people die, and you don't get that moment back.
你得去见她  告诉她你有多爱她
So you go and see her and you tell her how much you love her
以及你多懊悔让她失望了
and you tell her how sorry you are for letting her down.
得做到问心无愧
You clear your conscience.
重点是向她告别
This is about saying goodbye.
我给你这个机会  好好把握
I'm giving you that. Take it.
好吧  我会的
Okay, I will.
你这辅导员还不算太糟嘛
That wasn't bad. Your counseling.
你做得很好
You did a good job.
早安
Morning.
我给你带了些盆栽
I brought you some plants.
看到它们现在在小盆里了吗
They're in smaller pots, you see?
你要把它们种在这里面
You're gonna grow 'em in here?
不  是你来种
No, these are for you.
我才不把它们种这里面  我没时间
Uh, I'm not gonna grow in here. I don't have the time.
我会找新的休闲方式
I'll find some other way to relax.
一定要让红妈收到  行吗
Make sure Red gets those, okay?
如果你能有出狱一天的机会  你会想怎么使用
If you had one day on the outside, how would you spend it?
去我以前的市场  吃俄罗斯小馅饼
Oh... go to my market, taste the pirozhkis,
确保达米特里有继续在好好做
make sure Dimitri hasn't let it all go to shit.
吃什么  俄罗斯小什么
The what? The piroso... Pirosis?
小馅饼
Pirozhkis.
含馅的饼  跟肉饼很像
Stuffed buns, like a meat pie.
我以前做这个很出名
I was famous for them.
周日的时候店门外会大排长龙呢
On Sunday there'd be a line out the door.
是我一周中最喜欢的日子
It was my favorite day.
我能想象到顾客们跟家人嬉笑怒骂
I'd imagine the families laughing, talking, fighting,
一边吃着我的小馅饼
all while enjoying my pirozhkis.
店在皇后区  坐地铁N号线很快能到
It's in Queens, a quick ride on the N train.
你会去吗
Will you go?
去你的店吗
To your place?
我要不是担心  我也不会问
I wouldn't ask if I wasn't worried.
我希望有人能去帮我看看
I need someone to check it out,
点个三明治  看看店里
order a sandwich, take a look...
告诉我现在店里情况怎么样
let me know how it's running.
你不能叫你儿子们看吗
Can't you ask your sons?
我觉得他们没跟我说实话
I don't think they're being honest with me.
我知道你家里有事
I know you have family business.
如果不是很重要  我也不会麻烦你
I wouldn't ask if it wasn't important.
我不确定...
I'm not sure if...
我得去医院
I need to be at the hospital.
知道
Of course.
我不知道我有没有空
I don't know if I'll have time.
但我有空会去看看的
I'll go if I can.
你有空再去就行了
Only if you have time.
怎么说来着  小仙冰
How do you say that? Pirosees?
-小馅饼  -小馅饼
- Pirozhkis. - Pirozhkis.
美味一绝
The best.
这里是怎么回事
Hell, what's with the back up?
拉丁妞们头发太多了
Latin girls have a lot of hair.
你们这样是不对的
This is not right.
你们不能逼我洗澡  我又没有伤害到别人
You cannot force me to shower. I'm not hurting anybody.
我的鼻子不同意  而且收到四次投诉了
My nose would disagree, and four complaints have been filed.
规定里写着得定期洗澡
It's in the rules. You shower regularly.
这定期是谁定的
Who determines what's regular?
天哪  去C区吧
Christ. Let's go to C Block.
不要  我拒绝
No, I refuse.
我现在是被动反抗
I am demonstrating passive resistance.
我们是主动出击
We are demonstrating aggressive aggression.
宝佳康蒂[《风中奇缘》女主]  走吧
Let's go, Pocahontas.
-脱衣服  苏苏  -不要
- Off with it, Soso. - No!
贱人  你最好赶紧洗完
You better wash fast, bitch.
因为马上就会涌出屎了
Because a shit storm coming up out of there any second now.
科杰克
Hey, hey, hey, Kojak.
昨天怎么样了  有看到你的朋友吗
How'd it go yesterday? Did you see your little friend?
他在缓解期
He's in remission.
这是好事  对吧
That's wonderful, right?
对他来说是好事
Wonderful for him.
别这样  很快你也会没事的
Come on. Soon you'll be gettin' your clean bill of health.
不  我很快就要死了
No, soon I'm gonna be dead.
我一直以为自己会是在一片火光
I always pictured myself going out in a blaze of glory.
枪声四起  汽车爆冲的情景下离开
Hail of gunfire, screech of tires.
但这种死法
But this kind of death...
缓慢又看不见地
this slow, invisible...
让我的生命慢慢流逝
disappearing into nothing...
太可怕了
It's terrifying.
我要继续睡觉了
I'm gonna go back to sleep now.
这化疗让我精疲力尽
The chemo, it wipes me out.
你睡吧
Yeah. You do that.
喂
Hello?
妈  天哪  昨天我一直
Mom! God, I've been trying
想联系你们呢
to get in touch with you guys for the past day.
我被准假了
My furlough went through!
帕波
Piper?
我需要爸爸的车牌号  或者卡尔的
So, I need Daddy's license plate number or Cal's.
谁会来  还要一套换洗衣物
Who's coming? And, uh, a change of clothes.
-帕波  -换洗衣物
- Piper? - A change of clothes.
叫莱瑞把蓝色毛衣拿来  好像在波丽家
Um, tell Larry the blue sweater. I think it's at Polly's.
奶奶走了
Grandmother's gone.
她昨晚去世了
She passed last night.
但我要出去了
But I'm getting out.
亲爱的
Honey?
我错过了
I missed it.
你的精神与她同在
You were there in spirit.
帕波
Piper?
什么事  乔
Yes, Joe?
我昨天炒了费歇尔
I terminated Fischer yesterday.
她要拿到这个月的薪水
She needs to get paid through the end of the month.
你一定觉得很难受
That must've been hard for you.
别说了  我们本来就人手不足  她有可取之处
Please don't start. We're already understaffed. She had value.
你一定是这么认为的
I suppose you must've thought so.
我们不会被告性骚扰吧
We're not gonna get stuck with a sexual harassment suit, are we?
很好  至于人手问题
Good. As for the staffing issue,
我明白找到高质量人员不容易
I understand it's hard to find quality people.
在这个环境当中
It takes a certain kind of je
需要难以明说的品质增强效率
ne sais quoi to be effective in this environment.
"难以明说的品质"不会总是工作18小时的
"Je ne sais quoi" Doesn't always work for 18 an hour.
我聘用我能找到的最佳人选
I hire the best people I can find.
我知道你事情多
I know, and you're overwhelmed.
但我们需要更多人手  我会帮你找的
But we need some more muscle in here. I'm gonna help you out.
我自己来就行  谢了
I'll do my own hiring. Thank you.
已经帮你搞定了
It's already been taken care of.